Anh-Duy Tran

Doctoral Researcher in Software Security

□ anh-duy.tran@kuleuven.be
 https://pakkunandy.github.io/



I am a doctoral researcher in the research group **imec-DistriNet** at the Computer Science department of **KU Leuven**, under the supervision of **Prof. Wouter Joosen** and **Prof. Koen Yskout**. My research focuses include various subjects in Computer and System Security, mostly in Software Security, Computer and Multimedia Forensics, Malware Analysis, Mobile Security, and Privacy.

Education

2022 – Now **imec-Distrinet, KU Leuven**, Belgium **Doctoral Student**, Advisor: *Prof. Wouter Joosen & Prof. Koen Yskout Research*: Applying Automated Threat Modeling Based on Source Code

2017 – 2019 EURECOM and Polytechnic Institute of Paris - Telecom Paris, (Double Degree), France

M.Sc.Eng in Communication System Security, Advisor: Prof. Davide Balzarotti

Research: Analyzing Memory Images of Unknown Operating Systems

Thesis grade: 20/20

2016 – 2017 **John Von Neumann Institute, VNU-HCM**, Vietnam **M.Sc. in Data Science**

2012 - 2016 University of Science, VNU-HCM, Vietnam

B.Sc in Software Engineering, Advisor: Prof. Minh-Triet Tran

Research: Location-based Identity Management and Data Leak Prevention

Thesis grade: 10/10. Valedictorian

Work Experience

2019 – 2022 **University of Science, VNU-HCM**, *Lecturer and Researcher*, HCM, Vietnam. Subject: Software Development and Computer Security

2021 – 2022 **Inspire Lab Technology**, *Part-time Security Engineer*, HCM, Vietnam. Project: Solona-based DApp.

2020 – 2020 **KiteMetric**, *Part-time Security Consultant*, HCM, Vietnam. Project: Security Design for Web Application.

2019 – 2019 **S3 Group, EURECOM**, *Intern Scientist*, Nice, France.

Project: Memory Forensics.

2014 – 2014 **NEC Coprporation**, *Intern*, HCM, Vietnam.

Project: Android Application Development.

Selected Publications

- QRS 2023 Anh-Duy Tran, Koen Yskout, Wouter Joosen. 2023. AndrAS: Automated Attack Surface Extraction for Android Applications. International Conference on Software Quality, Reliability, and Security (QRS 2023).
- ACMMM Quang-Tien Tran, Thanh-Phuc Tran, Minh-Son Dao, Tuan-Vinh La, **Anh-Duy**2022 **Tran**, Duc Tien Dang Nguyen. 2022. A Textual-Visual-Entailment-based Unsupervised Algorithm for Cheapfake Detection. 30th ACM International Conference on Multimedia (ACMMM).
- ICIS 2022 Anh-Duy Tran, Quoc-Trung Nguyen, Anh-Minh Nguyen, Minh-Triet Tran. 2022.

 MemInspect2: OS-Independent Memory Forensics for IoT Devices in Cybercrime Investigations. IEEE/ACIS 22nd International Conference on Computer and Information Science (ICIS).
- SIN 2021 Truong-An Tran-Quoc, Minh-Chi Huynh, **Anh-Duy Tran**. 2021. <u>Towards OS-Independent Memory Images Analyzing: Using Paging Structures in Memory Forensics</u>. International Conference on Security of Information and Networks (SIN 2021).
- FDSE 2021 **Anh-Duy Tran**, Minh-Quan Nguyen, Gia-Hao Phan, and Minh-Triet Tran. 2021.

 Security Issues in Android Application Development and Plug-in for Android Studio to Support Secure Programming. The annual International Conference on Future Data and Security Engineering (FDSE).

Selected Awards

- 2023 Best paper award at QRS 2023.
- 2022 Certificate of Outstanding Young Lecturer at HCMUS.
- 2020 Certificate of Merit of Excellent Award in Cyber SEA game 2020, Ministry of Information and Communications.
- 2017 Eiffel Excellent Schlarship for Engineering Student.
- 2016 Second Prize in Vietnam National Competition for Innovation of Students XVIII.

Skills

Technical Java, C/C++, Android (at NEC Coprporation), Computer and Software Security, Memory Forensics (at EURECOM), Threat Modeling (at KU Leuven), Hacking skills (for CTF), Teaching skills

Language Vietnamese (native), and English (fluent)

Services

Organizers SCID @ AsiaCCS 2024, Cheapfake Grand Challenge @ ICMR 2024

PC Member MMM 2022, MAPR 2023-2024, SoICT 2023-2024, ICMR 2024, SecDev 2024

Reviewer JISA

AEC Member ACM CCS 2024, ISSTA 2024.

Secretary Vietnam Information Security Association, VNISA.

Founder Computer Security Club, HCMUS, VNU-HCMS